Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Serge Groussard. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Jean Guéhenno. Journal excerpts (includes G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Albert J. Guérard (Albert-Joseph Guérard. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Armel Guerne. Journal excerpt with G. S. notes(G. S. article, unpublished?). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Louis Guilloux. Press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed and handwritten manuscripts, G. S. notes. (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Gus. Typed manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Paul Guth. Book excerpt (G. S. preface), typed manuscript (Paul Guth, appears to be two incomplete articles). (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Daniel Halévy. Typed manuscript (Daniel Halévy 1872-1962). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Elie Halévy. Typed manuscript (Elie Halévy 1870-1937). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Nathaniel Hawthorne. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. article, Nathaniel Hawthorne). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Frédérique Hébrard. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article), typed manuscript (for the G. S. article, La chambre de goethe). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Franz Hellens. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Ernest Hemingway. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Hemingway par Quentin Ritzen), press clippings (including G. S. articles), journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Emile Henriot. Préface au tome 2 du XVIIIe siècle.... Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a preface with bibliography). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- John Hersey. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Richard Hillary. Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Homère. Typed mansuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, l'Iliade, Avant-propos). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Hugo (Victor Hugo). Book excerpt (G. S. article/chapter), journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscripts (a G. S. article, "Les Miserables Ont Cent Ans, and a G. S. preface), handwritten manuscript (a G. S. article/chapter on V. Hugo). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Pierre Humbourg. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Aldous Huxley. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, Huxley: Avant-Propos), G. S. notes. (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Istrati (Panait Istrati). Handwritten manuscript (G. S. preface). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Alexandre Jacob. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Henry James. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (a G. S. bibliography, Bibliographie Française d'Henry James), typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Ambassadeurs (Les)), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- René Jasinski. Gaz des lettres (c.46-48). Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Raymond Jean. Press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpts (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- P. J. Jouve (Pierre-Jean Jouve). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Paulina 1880). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- René Julliard. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. article, René Julliard). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Jung (Carl Gustav Jung). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, C. G. Jung). (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Kafka (Franz Kafka). Press clipping. (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Robert Kanters. Press clippings (2 copies of the same G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Kierkegaard (Søren Kierkegaard). Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Un Portrait de Kirkegaard), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Kinsey (Alfred C. Kinsey). Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Koestler (Arthur Koestler). Typed manuscript (a G. S. forward), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- La Bruyère (Jean de La Bruyère). Typed manuscript (a G. S. preface, includes a bibliography and chronology). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Laclos (Pierre-Ambroise-François Choderlus de Laclos). Typed manuscript (G. S. preface, Les Liaisons dangereuses - Préface). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Jacques de Lacretelle. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Jacques de Lacretelle). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Mme de La Fayette (Marie-Madeleine Pioche de la Vergne, comtesse de La Fayette). Press clipping (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, and 2 drafts of a G. S. preface). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- René Laporte. Press clippings (G. S. articles) (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Valery Larbaud. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscript (article, Valery Larbaud), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Léo Larguier. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Roland Laudenbach {Michel Braspart}. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- D. H. Lawrence (David Herbert Lawrence). Journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Paul Léautaud. Press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. article, Léautaud 1940-1941). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Lecomte du Nouy (Pierre Lecomte du Nouÿ). Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Frédéric Lefèvre. Press clippings (includes G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- G. S. sur I. L. (Ignace Legrand / Ignace Warschawsky). Book excerpt (G. S. preface), journal excerpts (G. S. articles), press clippings (obituaries and G. S. articles), typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a brief biography, 1 draft of a G. S. preface, 1 draft each of two different G. S. articles), G. S. notes. (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Edy Legrand. Journal and book excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- G. Lenotre (Théodore Gosselin Lenotre). Typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface - G. Lenotre ). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Jules Lequier. Typed manuscript (article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Gaston Leroux {G. S.}. Book advertisement pages, book excerpt (G. S. preface), typed manuscripts (G. S. prefaces and articles for a multi-volume work on G. Leroux). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Nicolas Leskov (Nicolas Semionovitch Leskov). Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Nicolas Leskov). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Sinclair Lewis. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article/preface, De Sang Royal: Sinclair Lewis; 1 draft of a G. S. article, Sinclair Lewis: Portrait; 1 handwritten draft of a G. S. article, Sinclair Lewis 1885-1951), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Albine Loisy (Albine Léger). Press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Jean Loisy. Press clippings (3 copies of a G. S. article) (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Malcolm Lowry. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Le Grand Lowry), press clippings (G. S. articles), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Georg Lukacs 1885. Typed manuscript. (Box 62, Folder 6)
- C. E. Magny (Claude-Edmonde Magny). Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Maurice Magre. Press clipping (G. S. article), journal excerpt (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Madame de Maintenon (Françoise d'Aubigné, Marquise de Maintenon). Typed and handwritten manuscript (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Madame de Maintenon: Préface). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Joseph de Maistre. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: Avec Joseph de Maistre; and Joseph de Maistre et Madame Swetchine). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Malaparte (Curzio Malaparte). Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Léo Malet. Correspondence (to G. S. from Léo Malet), typed manuscript (G. S. preface, Les chefs d'oeuvre du Roman policier: 120, rue de la Gare - Préface). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Thomas Mann. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: Thomas Mann et le Docteur Faustus; and Thomas Mann), press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article), G. S. notes, handwritten manuscript. (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Roger Martin du Gard. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Jules Mary. Journal excerpt, typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a J. P. Samet article, Il y a cent ans naissait Jules Mary). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Claude Mauriac. Journal and book excerpts (G. S. articles), handwritten and typed manuscript (G. S. article, Claude Mauriac), handwritten manuscript (Claude Mauriac: Romancier et essayiste). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- François Mauriac. Journal excerpts (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. preface and articles: François Mauriac: Romancier, essayiste, poète, auteur dramatique; 3 drafts of Introduction a Galigaï; Sur François Mauriac), press clipping (G. S. article), book excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- André Maurois. Handwritten manuscript, press clippings (including G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Maurras (Charles Maurras). Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Mazo de La Roche. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Jean-Jacques Mayoux. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Jean Meckert. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Melville (Herman Melville). Typed manuscripts (G. S. prefaces: Melville: Moby Dick - Avant-Propos de l'Éditeur; Israel Potter - Préface). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Maurice Merleau-Ponty. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of an article, Merleau-Ponty). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Merle Miller. Press clippings (4 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Milosz (Oscar-Vadislas de Lubicz-Milosz). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (4 drafts of a G. S. preface, L'Amoureuse Initiation). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Pierre Minet. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Pierre Moinot. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Henry Monnier. Journal excerpts (includes off-prints of a G. S. article), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles and prefaces: 2 drafts of Henry Monnier 1799-1877; 2 drafts of Comédie 1ere moitié XIX: Le Roman chez la portière - Henry Monnier; 2 drafts of Notes; and 1 draft of Henry Monnier "version radio"). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Montherlant (Henry Millon de Montherlant). Journal excerpts and press clippings(G. S. articles), G. S. notes. (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Robert de Montesquiou. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), handwritten manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Charles Morgan. Press clipping, journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Vladimir Nabokov. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Jacques Nels. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Nerval (Gérard de Nerval). Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Gérard de Nerval: La vie du théâtre). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Alfred Neumann. Book cover (for Neumann's Le Diable, with G. S. review). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Nietzsche (Friedrich Nietzsche). Journal excerpts (3 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Paul Nizan. Book excerpt (G. S. preface), journal excerpts (G. S. articles), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Paul Nizan: Romancier et Essayiste). (Box 62, Folder 7)
- O'Henry (William Sydney Porter). Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- George Orwell. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Albert Paraz. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Jean Paulhan. Press clipping (G.S. article), journal excerpts (G. S. excerpts), typed manuscript (article, Jean Paulhan). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Robert Penn Warren. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Vivette Perret. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Charles Plisnier. Typed manuscript (a J. P. Samet article, Écrivains d'aujourd'hui: Charles Plisnier). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Theodor Plievier. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Edgar Poe (Edgar Allen Poe). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. forward). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Jean Pommier. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), handwritten manuscript (article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Ponson du Terrail. Press clipping. (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Alexandre Pouchkine. Book excerpts with corrections (a G. S. introduction and an "Étude"), portions of typed and handwritten manuscripts, handwritten chronology, typed notes, typed bibliography. (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Robert Poulet. Press clippings (2 copies of a G.S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- J. C. Powys (John Cowper Powys). Typed manuscript (article), press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Marcel Pressac. Flyers (3 copies of a flyer advertising an art exhibit of M. Pressac's recent works, includes a G. S. article), handwritten and typed manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. article, Pressac). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Marcel Proust. Handwritten manuscripts (1 draft of an untitled article, and 2 different drafts of G. S. articles/prefaces, Proust et les Siens), professional correspondence (from G. d'Angelis to G. S.), journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Ernest Psichari. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Henriette Psichari. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Raymond Queneau. Typed manuscript (G.S. article), journal excerpts (3 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Thomas Raucat. Typed manuscript (G. S. preface, Préface - L'Honorable Partie de Campagne). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Jules Reboul. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Gustav Regler. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Henri de Réginier. Press clipping (includes G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Renan (Ernest Renan). Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article), typed notes or partial manuscript, handwritten manuscript (a G. S. speech?), correspondence (to G. S. from Corrie Siohan), invitations (4 copies of a flyer announcing a program of the Société des Études Renaniennes). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Richardson (Samuel Richardson). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Sur Clairisse Harlowe), G. S. notes, handwritten manuscript (Clarisse Harlowe). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- H. W. Richter (Hans Werner Richter). Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Rimbaud (Arthur Rimbaud). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), handwritten manuscript (G. S. article, La poésie, et aussi autre chose). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Alain Robbe-Grillet. Handwritten manuscript (article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Dominique Rolin. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Romain Rolland. Typed manuscripts (G. S. articles/prefaces: 1 draft of Romain Rolland. O.C. Théâtre. Tome 18, includes 2 drafts of the Notes, Bibliography, and Chronology); 2 drafts of Compagnons de Route - Préface; 1 draft of an untitled article, "Depuis la mort..."; 2 drafts of "Une place forte qu'il faut investir de tous les côtés..."; and 1 draft of an untitled article, "Je crois que..."), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Jules Romains. Press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: 2 drafts of Jules Romains (né en) 1885; 1 draft of Jules Romains). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Ronsard (Pierre de Ronsard). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface; 3 drafts a Chronology, Chronologie de la vie et de l'oeuvre de Ronsard; 1 draft of notes, Note pour la composition du livre). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Jean Rostand. Journal excerpts (includes G. S. articles), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles: 1 draft of Jean Rostand; 1 draft of Jean Rostand (2ex); and 1 draft of Jean Rostand (né en 1894)). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Joseph Roth. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, La Marche de Radetzky). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Jean-Jacques Rousseau. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. forward, Les livres qui ont fait le monde. Rousseau. Le Contrat Social. -- Avant-Propos de L'Éditeur), handwritten manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Jules Roy. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. articles: 3 drafts of La Valée Heureuse; 1 draft of Le Navigateur; 2 drafts of Jules Roy: Romancier, essayiste et auteur dramatique), press clippings (includes G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Claude Roy. Journal excerpt (G.S. article), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Damon Runyon. Press clippings (includes G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Bertrand Russell. Journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. article, Bertrand Russell). (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Françoise Sagan. Journal excerpts (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Françoise Sagan: Romancière). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Saint Exupéry (Antoine de Saint-Exupéry). Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- George Sand. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, George Sand - Préface). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- George Santayana. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- William Saroyan. Typed manuscript (Saroyan). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- J. P. Sartre (Jean-Paul Sartre). Press clippings (includes G. S. articles), G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscript (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Sartre (Jean-Paul)). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Marcel Schneider. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), press clipping (G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Reinhold Schneider. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Budd Schulberg. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Marcel Schwob. Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article), typed transcript (radio). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Francis Scott Fitzgerald. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Victor Serge. Book excerpt, journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Mme de Sévigné (Marie de Rabutin-Chantal, marquise de Sévigné). Book excerpt (a G. S. forward). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Irwin Shaw. Press clipping (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Silone (Ignazio Silone). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Claude Simon. Journal excerpt. (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Upton Sinclair. Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Manassas - Préface), press clippings (includes G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Jo Sinclair. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Frank Slaughter préface pour.... Typed manuscript (G. S. prefaceFrank G. Slaughter). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- C. P. Snow. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Georges Sorel. Typed manuscript (biography). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- André Soubiran. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article), typed manuscripts (G. S. articles: 2 drafts of, André Soubiran, 1 untitled draft, "S'il fallait étudier..."). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Robert Speaight. Journal excerpts (G. S. articles), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Robert Standish. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Jean Starobinski. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Gertrude Stein. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck. Press clippings (G. S. articles), typed manuscript (G. S. article, Au Dieu Inconnu). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Stendhal (Henri Beyle). Typed manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. article, Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde: Le Rouge et le Noir). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- R. L. Stevenson (Robert Louis Stevenson). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (5 drafts of a G. S. preface, La Flèche Noir / L'Ile au Trésor). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Bram Stoker. G. S. notes, typed and handwritten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. article/preface, Dracula, includes 4 drafts of a Bibliography). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Marie Stuart. Typed manuscript (G. S. article/preface, Marie Stuart dans la Littérature), typed chronology. (Box 63, Folder 4)
- André Suarès. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Swift (Johnathan Swift). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. forwards and articles: 2 drafts of Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde: Les Voyages de Gulliver -- Avant-Propos; 1 draft of Swift (Jonathan); 2 drafts of Brobdingnag; 2 drafts of Glubbdubdrid; 2 drafts of Gulliver; Houyhnhnms; 2 drafts of Laputa; 2 drafts of Lilliput; 2 drafts of Luggnagg), book excerpt (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- A. G. Swinburne. Typed and handwritten manuscripts (2 drafts of a G. S. preface, Préface à "Lesbia Brandon"). (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Taine (Hippolyte Taine). Typed manuscript/correspondence (from G. S. to François Ervel, a proposed index for a 3-volume work on Taine). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Booth Tarkington. Handwritten manuscript (G. S. article, Booth Tarkington). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Tchekov (Anton Tchekov). Typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. forwards and articles: 2 drafts of Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde: Tchekhov -- Avant-Propos de l'Éditeur; 1 draft of Tchekov), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Julien Teppe. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Albert Thibaudet. Journal excerpts, typed G. S. notes, typed manuscript (G. S. article, Thibaudet and La Suisse), press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Maurice Toesca. Press clippings (G. S. articles). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Tolstoï (Léon Tolstoï). Press clipping, book excerpt (G. S. preface), journal excerpts (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Touchard Lafosse. Handwritten manuscript (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Lionel Trilling. Journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Henri Troyat. Handwritten manuscript (G. S. article, La lumière des Justes -- La Barynia), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Roger Vailland. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Drôle de Jeu). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Maxence Van Der Meersch. Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Maxence Van Der Meersch), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Phillipe Van Tieghem... (Philippe van Tieghem Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Vassilioks. Typed notes. (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Lanza del Vasto. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Paul Vialar. Book excerpt (G. S. preface), typed and handwritten manuscripts (G. S. prefaces and articles: 3 drafts of Préface à l'Homme de Chasse: Paul Vialar; Écrivains d'aujourd'hui: Paul Vialar), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- {Reine} Victoria (Queen Victoria). Typed and handwrittten manuscripts (3 drafts of a G. S. preface, Les Femmes Célèbres. Elizabeth Longford: Victoria -- Préface). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Villiers de L'Isle Adam.Typed manuscript (G. S. article, Villiers de L'Isle-Adam a Travers sa Correspondence), press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Villon (François Villon). Book excerpt (G. S. article, photocopy), typed manuscript (G. S. article/preface, Romans historiques: François Villon). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Stephen Vincent Benet. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Vinci (Leonardo de Vinci). Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Voltaire (François Marie de Voltaire). Journal excerpt (G. S. article), typed manuscript (G. S. forward, Les Livres Qui Ont Fait Le Monde: Voltaire - Candide, Avant-Propos). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Bernard Voyenne. Press clipping (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Mary-Jane Ward. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Rex Warner. Press clipping. (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Jakob Wasserman. Press clippings (2 copies of a G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Evelyn Waugh. Press clippings (G. S. articles), journal excerpt (G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Simone Weil. Press clippings (includes G. S. article). (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Orson Welles. Typed manuscript (G. S. article/preface, Monsieur Arkedin). (Box 63, Folder 5)